
 const questions = [
    {
        question: "Which of these units can critically hit with their auto skill?",
        optionA: "Kuro",
        optionB: "Lam",
        optionC: "Hatsuchiri",
        optionD: "Max",
        correctOption: "optionB"
    },

    {
        question: "In Vulnerability Check 4, which of these bosses appear?",
        optionA: "Eucharist",
        optionB: "Angelus",
        optionC: "Faith",
        optionD: "Raven",
        correctOption: "optionA"
    },

    {
        question: "In Chapter/Sector 5, what did Eucharist described the Professor as?",
        optionA: "Lame and Weak",
        optionB: "A Creep",
        optionC: "Sleep Deprived and Sickly",
        optionD: "Very Handsome and Cool",
        correctOption: "optionC"
    },

    {
        question: "In Chapter/Sector 6, why did Odile kill Demiurge?",
        optionA: "To remove another 'Arbiter'",
        optionB: "Because she just wanted to",
        optionC: "She did it in self-defense",
        optionD: "Thought Demiurge was a threat",
        correctOption: "optionA"
    },

    {
        question: "Which of these Sanctifiers has aided the Professor?",
        optionA: "Eosphorus",
        optionB: "Angelus",
        optionC: "Patience",
        optionD: "Punishment",
        correctOption: "optionA"
    },

    {
        question: "In Chapter/Sector 6, How did the Professor call for help?",
        optionA: "Using Admin Permissions to call the Sanctifiers",
        optionB: "Persuaded a stranded Sanctifier to call for back-up",
        optionC: "They did not, a threat was big enough to alert them.",
        optionD: "They did not, they were there to kill the Professor.",
        correctOption: "optionA"
    },

    {
        question: "Which of these Enigma Black Hole floors are generally considered hard?",
        optionA: "Floor 80",
        optionB: "Floor 127",
        optionC: "Floor 105",
        optionD: "Floor 134",
        correctOption: "optionA"
    },

    {
        question: "In Chapter/Sector 1, what weakened Faith?",
        optionA: "Antonina's Trojan slowing her down",
        optionB: "Weakened after multiple battles",
        optionC: "Hannah's Re:Write plan",
        optionD: "Unintentionally killing Turing",
        correctOption: "optionD"
    },

    {
        question: "In Chapter/Sector 4, why did the Professor let Angelus go?",
        optionA: "Because it may help them more than winning",
        optionB: "Because the Professor felt pity for Angelus",
        optionC: "Because Persicaria could no longer continue fighting",
        optionD: "They didn't, Angelus just retreated",
        correctOption: "optionD"
    },

    {
        question: "Why is Angela considered one of the best units?",
        optionA: "She decreases foes' Operand Defense and increases allies Hashrate",
        optionB: "She lets your allies skill faster and delays foes from skilling",
        optionC: "She can deal large amounts of damage even without functions",
        optionD: "She gives allies stats when they have killed a foe",
        correctOption: "optionB"
    },

    {
        question: "Which of these Algorithm sets are not real?",
        optionA: "Encapsulation",
        optionB: "M.L.R Matrix",
        optionC: "Reiteration",
        optionD: "Connection",
        correctOption: "optionC"
    },

    {
        question: "How many Pioneering(Gold) Breakthrough Widgets does Breakthrough 6 need?",
        optionA: "120",
        optionB: "130",
        optionC: "135",
        optionD: "125",
        correctOption: "optionB"
    },


    {
        question: "How much EXP is needed to reach Level 70 from 60?",
        optionA: "652555",
        optionB: "599500",
        optionC: "600000",
        optionD: "700000",
        correctOption: "optionC"
    },

    {
        question: "Which of these dolls also appear in Girls: Frontline?",
        optionA: "Croque",
        optionB: "Dushevnaya",
        optionC: "Hatsuchiri",
        optionD: "Angela",
        correctOption: "optionB"
    },

    {
        question: "Which of these classes does Choco belong to?",
        optionA: "Specialist",
        optionB: "Sniper",
        optionC: "Guard",
        optionD: "Medic",
        correctOption: "optionD"
    },

    {
        question: "Which of these units appear in the story of Chapter 5-Dark Realm?",
        optionA: "Jesse",
        optionB: "Persicaria",
        optionC: "Riko",
        optionD: "Raven",
        correctOption: "optionC"
    },

    {
        question: "How would one unlock non-shop or battle pass costumes/projections?",
        optionA: "Reaching 3.5* and 4* Neural Expansion",
        optionB: "Reaching Unit lvl 70",
        optionC: "Reacing Intimacy lvl 15",
        optionD: "Reaching 5* Neural Expansion",
        correctOption: "optionA"
    },

    {
        question: "What is the gimmick of Chapter 5?",
        optionA: "Electromagnetic Radiation Devices",
        optionB: "Entropics/Entropic Tiles",
        optionC: "Pseudo-Energy Herb/Herb Tiles",
        optionD: "Tidal Waves/Entropic Tidal Waves",
        correctOption: "optionB"
    },

    {
        question: "Why is Enigma Black Hole's gameplay considered vastly different?",
        optionA: "No Algorithms/Equips",
        optionB: "It is a Tower Defense gamemode",
        optionC: "No Specialty Training",
        optionD: "No Function Cards or Protocols",
        correctOption: "optionD"
    },

    {
        question: "What is one existing Procedural Upgrade?",
        optionA: "Function Card Compatibilization",
        optionB: "Ultimate Recharge Boost",
        optionC: "Churning Tidal Waves",
        optionD: "Tactical Point Compatibilization",
        correctOption: "optionD"
    },

    {
        question: "How many Specialty Training points you get from one unit per key?",
        optionA: "Eleven",
        optionB: "Eight",
        optionC: "Nine",
        optionD: "Seven",
        correctOption: "optionB"
    },

    {
        question: "What is the current max Oasis level?",
        optionA: "Lvl. 108",
        optionB: "Lvl. 110",
        optionC: "Lvl. 117",
        optionD: "Lvl. 125",
        correctOption: "optionC"
    },

    {
        question: "Which time-zone does Neural Cloud use for Maintenance and Daily Resets?",
        optionA: "GMT 0",
        optionB: "GMT-8",
        optionC: "GMT-3",
        optionD: "GMT+8",
        correctOption: "optionB"
    },

    {
        question: "In the standard shop, how much would 2 Pioneering/gold Breakthrough Widgets cost?",
        optionA: "5000 Diggcoins",
        optionB: "60 Ether Tokens",
        optionC: "10 Quartz Sands",
        optionD: "50 Glitter Chips",
        correctOption: "optionA"
    },

    {
        question: "Assuming 5* Neural Expansion and Lvl 70, How much base Hashrate does Kuro has?",
        optionA: "630",
        optionB: "702",
        optionC: "583",
        optionD: "689",
        correctOption: "optionD"
    }

]


let shuffledQuestions = [] //empty array to hold shuffled selected questions out of all available questions

function handleQuestions() { 
    //function to shuffle and push 10 questions to shuffledQuestions array
//app would be dealing with 10questions per session
    while (shuffledQuestions.length <= 9) {
        const random = questions[Math.floor(Math.random() * questions.length)]
        if (!shuffledQuestions.includes(random)) {
            shuffledQuestions.push(random)
        }
    }
}


let questionNumber = 1 //holds the current question number
let playerScore = 0  //holds the player score
let wrongAttempt = 0 //amount of wrong answers picked by player
let indexNumber = 0 //will be used in displaying next question

// function for displaying next question in the array to dom
//also handles displaying players and quiz information to dom
function NextQuestion(index) {
    handleQuestions()
    const currentQuestion = shuffledQuestions[index]
    document.getElementById("question-number").innerHTML = questionNumber
    document.getElementById("player-score").innerHTML = playerScore
    document.getElementById("display-question").innerHTML = currentQuestion.question;
    document.getElementById("option-one-label").innerHTML = currentQuestion.optionA;
    document.getElementById("option-two-label").innerHTML = currentQuestion.optionB;
    document.getElementById("option-three-label").innerHTML = currentQuestion.optionC;
    document.getElementById("option-four-label").innerHTML = currentQuestion.optionD;

}


function checkForAnswer() {
    const currentQuestion = shuffledQuestions[indexNumber] //gets current Question 
    const currentQuestionAnswer = currentQuestion.correctOption //gets current Question's answer
    const options = document.getElementsByName("option"); //gets all elements in dom with name of 'option' (in this the radio inputs)
    let correctOption = null

    options.forEach((option) => {
        if (option.value === currentQuestionAnswer) {
            //get's correct's radio input with correct answer
            correctOption = option.labels[0].id
        }
    })

    //checking to make sure a radio input has been checked or an option being chosen
    if (options[0].checked === false && options[1].checked === false && options[2].checked === false && options[3].checked == false) {
        document.getElementById('option-modal').style.display = "flex"
    }

    //checking if checked radio button is same as answer
    options.forEach((option) => {
        if (option.checked === true && option.value === currentQuestionAnswer) {
            document.getElementById(correctOption).style.backgroundColor = "green"
            playerScore++ //adding to player's score
            indexNumber++ //adding 1 to index so has to display next question..
            //set to delay question number till when next question loads
            setTimeout(() => {
                questionNumber++
            }, 1000)
        }

        else if (option.checked && option.value !== currentQuestionAnswer) {
            const wrongLabelId = option.labels[0].id
            document.getElementById(wrongLabelId).style.backgroundColor = "red"
            document.getElementById(correctOption).style.backgroundColor = "green"
            wrongAttempt++ //adds 1 to wrong attempts 
            indexNumber++
            //set to delay question number till when next question loads
            setTimeout(() => {
                questionNumber++
            }, 1000)
        }
    })
}



//called when the next button is called
function handleNextQuestion() {
    checkForAnswer() //check if player picked right or wrong option
    unCheckRadioButtons()
    //delays next question displaying for a second just for some effects so questions don't rush in on player
    setTimeout(() => {
        if (indexNumber <= 9) {
//displays next question as long as index number isn't greater than 9, remember index number starts from 0, so index 9 is question 10
            NextQuestion(indexNumber)
        }
        else {
            handleEndGame()//ends game if index number greater than 9 meaning we're already at the 10th question
        }
        resetOptionBackground()
    }, 1000);
}

//sets options background back to null after display the right/wrong colors
function resetOptionBackground() {
    const options = document.getElementsByName("option");
    options.forEach((option) => {
        document.getElementById(option.labels[0].id).style.backgroundColor = ""
    })
}

// unchecking all radio buttons for next question(can be done with map or foreach loop also)
function unCheckRadioButtons() {
    const options = document.getElementsByName("option");
    for (let i = 0; i < options.length; i++) {
        options[i].checked = false;
    }
}

// function for when all questions being answered
function handleEndGame() {
    let remark = null
    let remarkColor = null

    // condition check for player remark and remark color
    if (playerScore <= 3) {
        remark = "Bad Grades, Keep Practicing."
        remarkColor = "red"
    }
    else if (playerScore >= 4 && playerScore < 7) {
        remark = "Average Grades, You can do better."
        remarkColor = "orange"
    }
    else if (playerScore >= 7) {
        remark = "Excellent, Keep the good work going."
        remarkColor = "green"
    }
    const playerGrade = (playerScore / 10) * 100

    //data to display to score board
    document.getElementById('remarks').innerHTML = remark
    document.getElementById('remarks').style.color = remarkColor
    document.getElementById('grade-percentage').innerHTML = playerGrade
    document.getElementById('wrong-answers').innerHTML = wrongAttempt
    document.getElementById('right-answers').innerHTML = playerScore
    document.getElementById('score-modal').style.display = "flex"

}

//closes score modal, resets game and reshuffles questions
function closeScoreModal() {
    questionNumber = 1
    playerScore = 0
    wrongAttempt = 0
    indexNumber = 0
    shuffledQuestions = []
    NextQuestion(indexNumber)
    document.getElementById('score-modal').style.display = "none"
}

//function to close warning modal
function closeOptionModal() {
    document.getElementById('option-modal').style.display = "none"
}